Kolten Edward

Software Engineer

koltenedward@proton.me • 720-515-7373 • koltenedward.com • github.com/kdten

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

100DevsLos Angeles, CASoftware Engineer08/2022 - Current

- Enhanced project delivery speed and team productivity by implementing Agile/Scrum methodologies, achieving an 18% increase in sprint completion rates, from 110 tickets to 130.
- Increased the production deployment speed by 28% from x deployments per week to y, by optimizing our AWS CodePipelines, using CI/CD best practices, such as alarm blockers, and automatic rollbacks.
- Developed RESTful API using Node Express, leveraging TypeScript for strong typing, delivering features like authentication, caching, and rate limiting to boost application functionality and scalability.
- Achieved a 31% reduction in cross-platform application development time, from 132 days to 41, by leveraging Ionic React for simultaneous iOS and Android deployments from a single JavaScript codebase.

Frontend Engineer 03/2021 - 08/2022

- Improved user engagement by 22% from 1,400 weekly visits to 1,710, by refactoring the code using Pug and Bootstrap, taking advantage of responsive layouts for a better CX.
- Led the adoption of automated front-end testing, reducing manual testing time by 70% from 5 days to 1.5 days, enhancing code quality with Jest, Selenium.
- Optimized web application performance, cutting load times by 74% from 1.655 s to 426 ms, and increasing conversion rates by 17% from 1.98% to 2.32%, by using techniques such as lazy loading, caching, and AJAX.
- Maintained a web application used daily by 89 customers, with minimal reported bugs, by investing in unit testing, and canary alarms.

2017-2021: Supervisor in various depts at Costco Wholesale, increased executive membership 8% YoY

CAREER SUMMARY

Experience 3+ years in full stack development working with Typescript, React, Redux, Node, Express

Languages Typescript, JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Testing Cypress, Jest, Mocha, Chai

Frontend React, Redux, NextJS, Ionic/Capacitor, Playwright, Tailwind CSS

Backend NodeJS, Express, Mocha, Chai, MongoDB, GraphQL, RESTful API, Stripe

Cloud AWS - IAM, EC2, S3, EFS, CloudFront, Lightsail, CodePipline, VPC

GCP - Firebase, Document AI

Tools Docker, Git, CI/CD

EDUCATION

North Iowa Area Community College Associate of Arts

Mason City, IA 2008 – 2010